in this video we're going to look at how
在本视频中，我们将探讨
to define utility in infinitely repeated
无限重复地定义效用
games so remember that the way that an
游戏，所以请记住
infinitely repeated game works is that
无限重复的游戏作品是
we have some stage game which is a
我们有一些舞台游戏
normal form game and the players
普通形式的游戏和玩家
repeatedly played this same game over
反复玩过同一游戏
and over again and what that means is
一遍又一遍，这意味着
each player gets a sequence of payoffs
每个玩家都有一系列的回报
let's say player AI gets the sequence
假设玩家AI获得了序列
are one in the first repetition are two
在第一次重复中是两个
in the second repetition are three just
在第二次重复中，三个
on and on infinitely so we have this
持续不断，所以我们有这个
infinite sequence of real values which
实数的无限序列
are the payoffs that this player has
是该玩家的收益
gotten but if we want to reason about
得到了，但如果我们想推理一下
this game we can't really reason using
这个游戏我们真的不能使用
utility theory of an infinite sequence
无限序列的效用理论
we instead have to take this sequence
相反，我们必须按照这个顺序
and turn it into a single number that
并将其转换为一个数字
talks about the utility that the player
谈论播放器的实用程序
has for having played this sequence and
已经玩过这个顺序了
so how do we do that what's the right
那么我们该怎么做才是正确的
way of thinking about that so the first
这样思考的方式，所以第一个
thing to notice is that previous things
需要注意的是以前的事情
that we've learned about game theory
我们已经了解了博弈论
aren't going to be sufficient to answer
不足以回答
this question so you might wonder if we
这个问题，所以您可能想知道我们是否
can take this infinitely repeated game
可以参加这个无限重复的游戏
and just write it an extensive form and
然后将其写成广泛的形式
of course we can't and the reason is
我们当然不能，原因是
that the extensive form would be
广泛的形式是
infinitely deep we would never get to a
无限深，我们将永远不会
leaf node where we could write a payoff
我们可以写收益的叶节点
and so that won't help us you might also
这样对我们没有帮助，您可能也
just wonder can we sum up the sequence
只是想知道我们可以总结一下顺序
of payoffs and just say that my utility
回报，只是说我的效用
is the the sum of these values and the
是这些值的总和
problem is that that some can be
问题是，有些可以
unbounded because if for example every
无界的，因为例如
payoff I get is positive then I'm gonna
我得到的回报是正数，那么我要
have some unbounded amount of utility at
拥有无限的效用
the end and so that that's not going to
结束，所以这不会
work for me I want to have finite
为我工作我想要有限
utilities so instead there are two
实用程序，所以有两个
canonical ways that this gets defined
定义的规范方法
and I'll tell you about both of them in
我会在这件事上告诉你
this video so here's the first one so
这个视频，所以这是第一个
the first thing says let me look
第一件事说让我看
intuitively at my average payoff over
凭直觉，我的平均收益超过
this sequence now the average payoff of
现在这个序列的平均收益为
a sequence is also not well-defined
序列也没有明确定义
because of course the way I take your
因为我当然以你的方式
average is I sum everything up and then
平均来说，我把所有东西都加起来
I divide it by the number of things and
我将其除以事物的数量，
we've already seen that this sum can be
我们已经看到，这笔款项可以是
unbounded the number of things is
事物的数量是无限的
unbounded as well so I would have
无界的，所以我会
infinity divided
无限除
infinity which wouldn't help me out here
无穷无尽，这对我没有帮助
but what I can do instead is to look at
但我能做的就是看
the limit of finite averages as the
有限平均数的极限为
averages get longer and longer so what I
平均数越来越长，所以我
can say is let me look at an average
可以说是让我看一个平均值
over the first K things in my sequence
在我序列中的前K个事物中
and then let me take the limit of this
然后让我限制一下
average as K goes to infinity and it
当K达到无穷大时，它的平均值
turns out actually technically this
实际上从技术上证明了这一点
isn't always well-defined it's almost
并不总是很明确，几乎
always well-defined and there's an easy
总是定义明确，并且很容易
fix that we can do to this definition
修正我们可以对此定义进行的操作
that I've left out here to keep it from
我已经留在这里，以防止它
getting too technical but in cases where
变得过于技术化，但在某些情况下
this is well-defined
这是明确的
this is the right thing to do so and and
这是正确的做法，并且
everything we'll talk about in this
我们将在此谈论的一切
course it'll be well-defined so so this
当然，它会被很好地定义，所以这
is the defined as the average reward
被定义为平均奖励
that the planner gets over the infinite
计划者克服了无限
sequence and this gives us one number
序列，这给了我们一个数字
the reason we have a second definition
我们有第二个定义的原因
is that there's something kind of
是某种东西
counterintuitive about the average
关于平均数的直觉
reward let me put it back up the reason
奖励让我把它备份的原因
that it's kind of counterintuitive is
这有点违反直觉的是
that if I get some bad payoff for a
如果我得到了一些不好的回报
finite amount of time let's say for the
有限的时间让我们说
first hundred thousand iterations I get
我得到的前十万次迭代
a payoff of negative a million and then
负一百万的回报，然后
for the rest of time after that I get
在那之后的剩余时间里
some good payoff let's say one unit of
可以说一个好回报
utility then the limit of the means
效用然后是手段的极限
would be one because the the negative
将会是一个，因为负面的
payoff that I got at the beginning was
我一开始得到的回报是
only for a finite amount of time and it
只在有限的时间内
washes out in the average if I go long
如果我走多久，平均会被洗掉
enough out into the future and well
足够远的将来
that's what the math says but that
这就是数学所说的，但是
doesn't always model what we want to to
并不总是为我们想要的模型
really reason about because we have an
真正原因是因为我们有一个
intuition that payoffs that you get it
直觉使你得到回报
early on are kind of more important than
早于比
payoffs that you get really far into the
您获得的收益确实很大
future so if we want to have a model of
未来，所以如果我们想要一个模型
utility that has that property we need
具有我们需要的属性的实用程序
to say that different payoffs matter
说不同的收益很重要
differently so it's more important to me
不同，所以对我来说更重要
to get a good payoff in the first
在第一时间获得良好的回报
iteration than to get one in the
迭代比获得之一
millionth iteration and the way that I
第百万次迭代以及我的方式
can model that is by saying my payoffs
可以通过说我的收益来建模
are multiplied by some discount factor
乘以一些折扣系数
so my discount factor talks about my
所以我的折扣因素是关于我的
value for payoffs at different times so
在不同时间的回报价值
my discount factor beta is some value
我的折现系数beta有一定价值
strictly between 0 & 1 and you can sort
严格在0和1之间，您可以排序
of think of it like an interest rate
想像是利率
it's saying you know with money if
就是说你知道有钱
I wanted to tell somebody that I'm gonna
我想告诉某人我要
pay them a hundred dollars in a year
一年付一百美元
they would value that at less than a
他们会认为该价格低于
hundred dollars today and so and the
今天一百美元等等
amount by which they would value it less
他们将其贬值的金额
today kind of corresponds to the
今天的对应于
interest rate and that's kind of exactly
利率，这恰好是
what's going on in the math here so what
数学在这里发生了什么
I'm saying here is that my utility for
我是说我的工具
this stream of payoffs this stream of
这股回报之流
ours the stream of payoffs is weighted
我们的收益流是加权的
by the discount factor ^ which path in
通过折现因子^哪条路径
the sequence it is so I'm going to
这是顺序，所以我要
discount each payoff successively so the
依次贴现每个收益，因此
first one it's going to have the
第一个将有
discount factor applied once the second
每秒应用一次折扣系数
one is going to have the discount factor
一个将有折扣因素
applied twice so I'm going to get the
申请了两次，所以我要去
discount factor squared and so on all
折扣系数平方等
the way through the sequence so each of
通过序列的方式，所以每个
them is going to be diminished but each
他们将减少，但每个
of them is still going to matter and
他们中的仍然很重要，
there are two ways we can think about
我们可以考虑两种方法
what the discount factor means so the
折扣因素意味着什么
first is kind of the interpretation that
首先是那种解释
I've been telling you so far but the
到目前为止，我一直在告诉您，但是
agent just cares more about the near
特工只是在乎附近
term than the long term there's another
远比长期而言
definition which is different but
定义不同但
mathematically are the same so it's
数学上是一样的，所以
interesting to think about and that is
想起来很有趣，那就是
that the agent really is the agent we
那个代理商真的是我们的代理商
just talked about in the average reward
刚刚在平均奖励中谈到
case cares just as much about every
案件在乎每个人
payoff but with some probability the
回报，但有可能
probability actually 1 minus beta the
概率实际上是1减去beta
game will end in every given round so
游戏将在每个给定回合中结束，因此
our game is not necessarily infinitely
我们的游戏不一定是无限的
repeated it's sort of potentially
重复它有点潜在
infinitely repeated but every time we
无限重复，但每次我们
play the game we're gonna flip a coin
玩我们要掷硬币的游戏
and with probability 1 minus beta the
并以1减去beta的概率
game is going to just end and with
游戏即将结束，
probability beta the game is going to
游戏的概率beta
continue and what that means is that
继续，那是什么意思
here we be talking about my expected
在这里，我们正在谈论我的期望
reward in the game because there's a a
在游戏中奖励，因为有一个
beta chance that I'll go to the next
Beta机会，我会去下一个
round there's a beta squared chance that
大约有一个beta平方的机会
I'm gonna go two rounds forward the beta
我要进行两轮测试
cube chance I'm gonna go three rounds
我要去三回合的机会
forward and so on so that means my
前进等等，这意味着我
expected utility in this game would
在这个游戏中的预期效用
would just be the same formula and
将只是相同的公式，
that's it for defining utility in these
就是在这些中定义实用程序
games thanks very much
游戏非常感谢